[
    {
      "id": 1,
      "correct-answer": 2,
      "question": "Where is Scott Base?",
      "answer1": "Stewart Island",
      "answer2": "Antarctica",
      "answer3": "South Island",
      "answer4": "New York in the USA"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "correct-answer": 2,
      "question": "How did the first Polynesian settlers travel to NZ?",
      "answer1": "By plane",
      "answer2": "By boat",
      "answer3": "By jetski",
      "answer4": "By horse"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "correct-answer": 2,
      "question": "Which insect provides some light in caves such as the Waitomo Caves?",
      "answer1": "Candle-worms",
      "answer2": "Glow-worms",
      "answer3": "Silkworm",
      "answer4": "Slow worm"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "correct-answer": 4,
      "question": "What colour is Kakariki?",
      "answer1": "Blue",
      "answer2": "Yellow",
      "answer3": "Black",
      "answer4": "Green"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "correct-answer": 3,
      "question": "What is the public holiday held to remember the soldiers from Australia and NZ who fought at Gallipoli, Turkey?",
      "answer1": "Waitangi Day",
      "answer2": "Remembrance Day",
      "answer3": "Anzac Day",
      "answer4": "Matariki"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "correct-answer": 2,
      "question": "What is the name of the beach on the Coromandel Peninsula where you can dig and find hot water?",
      "answer1": "90 Mile Beach",
      "answer2": "Hot Water Beach",
      "answer3": "Piha Beach",
      "answer4": "Mission Bay"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "correct-answer": 3,
      "question": "What nocturnal pouched animal has a devastating effect on NZâ€™s forests?",
      "answer1": "Kangaroo",
      "answer2": "Cats",
      "answer3": "Possums",
      "answer4": "Hedgehogs"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "correct-answer": 2,
      "question": "Edmund Hillary and Sherpa Tenzing Norgay were the first men to climb which mountain?",
      "answer1": "Mount Ranginui",
      "answer2": "Mount Everest",
      "answer3": "Mount Ruapehu",
      "answer4": "Mount Taranaki"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "correct-answer": 4,
      "question": "Which one of these animals is native to NZ?",
      "answer1": "Deer",
      "answer2": "Goat",
      "answer3": "Pig",
      "answer4": "Long-tailed bat",
      "answer5": "Horse"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "correct-answer": 3,
      "question": "What is geothermal power?",
      "answer1": "Electric power that makes the earth warmer",
      "answer2": "Electric power that makes the earth cooler",
      "answer3": "Electric power generated from geothermal sources",
      "answer4": "Electric power generated from metal"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "correct-answer": 1,
      "question": "The first ever ANZAC Day marches were held in London and Australia in which year?",
      "answer1": 1916,
      "answer2": 1926,
      "answer3": 1936,
      "answer4": 1946
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "correct-answer": 1,
      "question": "Auckland is situated in which gulf?",
      "answer1": "Hauraki Gulf",
      "answer2": "Gulf of Aden",
      "answer3": "Persian Gulf",
      "answer4": "Gulf of Riga"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "correct-answer": 3,
      "question": "Which NZ bird has a tail like a fan?",
      "answer1": "Fanbird",
      "answer2": "Kiwi",
      "answer3": "Fantail",
      "answer4": "Kakapo"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "correct-answer": 3,
      "question": "Scurvy was a disease that mainly affected which people?",
      "answer1": "Hunters",
      "answer2": "Fishermen",
      "answer3": "Sailors",
      "answer4": "Businessmen"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "correct-answer": 3,
      "question": "Julie Anne Genter, Simon Bridges, Louisa Wall, Andrew Little, Paula Bennet and Winston Peters are all what?",
      "answer1": "Authors",
      "answer2": "Businesspeople",
      "answer3": "Politicians",
      "answer4": "Comedians"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "correct-answer": 4,
      "question": "In which of these countries have NZ soldiers never fought a war?",
      "answer1": "South Africa",
      "answer2": "Korea",
      "answer3": "Vietnam",
      "answer4": "Brazil"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "correct-answer": 2,
      "question": "Which town is the entry to the South Island, where the Cook Strait ferry passengers disembark?",
      "answer1": "Queenstown",
      "answer2": "Picton",
      "answer3": "Invercargill",
      "answer4": "New Plymouth"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "correct-answer": 4,
      "question": "What is the speed limit on the open road?",
      "answer1": "50km/h",
      "answer2": "60km/h",
      "answer3": "120km/h",
      "answer4": "100km/h"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "correct-answer": 2,
      "question": "Who were the leaders of Maori tribes?",
      "answer1": "Captains",
      "answer2": "Chiefs",
      "answer3": "Heads",
      "answer4": "Pilots"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "correct-answer": 2,
      "question": "Which large flightless birds were hunted to extinction in NZ?",
      "answer1": "Kiwi",
      "answer2": "Moa",
      "answer3": "Kakapo",
      "answer4": "Tuatara"
    },
    {
      "id": 21,
      "correct-answer": 4,
      "question": "NZ has about 2,700 native plant species. Since the arrival of Europeans, how many new plant species have been introduced?",
      "answer1": 20,
      "answer2": 200,
      "answer3": 2000,
      "answer4": 20000
    },
    {
      "id": 22,
      "correct-answer": 1,
      "question": "Which city is the home of Otago University?",
      "answer1": "Dunedin",
      "answer2": "Auckland",
      "answer3": "Wellington",
      "answer4": "Christchurch"
    },
    {
      "id": 23,
      "correct-answer": 3,
      "question": "What is the name of the strait between the North and South Islands?",
      "answer1": "Stewart Strait",
      "answer2": "Foveaux Strait",
      "answer3": "Cook Strait",
      "answer4": "Tamaki Strait"
    },
    {
      "id": 24,
      "level": 2,
      "correct-answer": 1,
      "question": "What year was the Treaty of Waitangi signed?",
      "answer1": 1840,
      "answer2": 1940,
      "answer3": 1841,
      "answer4": 1759
    },
    {
      "id": 25,
      "level": 3,
      "correct-answer": 4,
      "question": "What is the large edible bivalve, prized for the meat and the greenish soup made from it?",
      "answer1": "Pie",
      "answer2": "Whare",
      "answer3": "Tuna",
      "answer4": "Toheroa"
    },
    {
      "id": 26,
      "level": 4,
      "correct-answer": 1,
      "question": "At the outbreak of World War 1, NZ troops were sent to capture which Pacific island?",
      "answer1": "Western Samoa",
      "answer2": "Stewart Island",
      "answer3": "Tasmania",
      "answer4": "Apolima"
    }
  ]